pima.gov 2019-08-30

# HIPAA/Privacy Statement - Pima County

## 1\. Services provided

This web site provides selected services and information to the constituency of Pima County. Neither Pima County nor any agency, officer, or employee of Pima County warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.

The Pima County web site contains links to other non-county (external) web sites. Links to other web sites do not constitute an endorsement by Pima County. Such external web sites contain information and services that have been created independently of the Pima County web site, and they are only provided as a convenience for our site visitors who may need additional information that we do not control, or otherwise cannot provide. Pima County does not endorse, approve, certify or control these external web sites, nor any of the information and data contained on those web sites. Pima County cannot guarantee the privacy of your personal information while accessing those web sites. Pima County encourages visitors to check the privacy policies of all external web sites visited, and to be cautious about providing personal information while on these sites without first obtaining a clear understanding of how such information will be used. Many non-county sites may gather information which may be subject to disclosure under the public records laws and other provisions of state or federal law.

## 2\. Information gathered from users

Pima County collects no personally identifying information about individuals except when specifically and knowingly provided by such individuals. In addition, Pima County Web servers may place a "cookie" on the hard drive of a user's computer. The cookie itself does not contain any personally identifying information.

Among the information that may be collected to manage the communications between the server and the browser are: 

  * The name of the domain and IP address from which you access our web site 
  * The type of browser used to access our site 
  * The date and time of access 
  * The Internet address of the web site from which you linked directly to our site 
  * The pages you visit 
  * Sections of the web site you attempted to visit but were unable to access due to programming or other technical problems. 

All e-mail addresses maintained by Pima County contain the names of people who voluntarily communicated with or requested information from us.

No applications, services or surveys on the Pima County web site seek to determine or verify the age of site visitors. Consequently, visitors should be aware that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by minors online or by e-mail will be treated in the same manner as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access as prescribed by applicable laws. We advise children (minors) to get their parents' permission before providing any information online.

## 3\. Alternatives to using this web site

Information provided by this web site can also be accessed by visiting the appropriate Pima County office. Pima County provides access to all of its public records. This web site is one means for providing information.

## 4\. Use of the data gathered by this web site

The vast majority of the information collected by Pima County Web servers is used to manage communications between the server and the browser.

## 5\. Disclosure of gathered data

Pima County does not sell, trade or rent Pima County web site visitor information, including electronic mail addresses, to any outside company or organization. Pima County will not disclose personally identifiable information or credit/debit card information to third parties, except for the purposes of completing your payment transaction through a secured financial network or to collection agencies.

Pima County may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide personally identifiable information, or credit/debit card data, to the appropriate governmental authorities as required by law.

If you provide personal information, the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information may be considered public record, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal law or state law.

## 6\. Third party information gathering

Pima County does not allow third parties to gather information from users of its web sites.

## 7\. HIPAA/Privacy Practices

Pima County is required by law to take reasonable steps to ensure the privacy of personally identifiable health information and to inform individuals about: 

  * Pima County's uses and disclosures of PHI; 
  * Your rights with respect to your PHI; 
  * Pima County's duties with respect to PHI; 
  * Your right to file a complaint with Pima County and to the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; and 
  * The identification of the person or office to contact for further information about Pima County's privacy practices. 

Please learn more by visiting our [HIPAA/Privacy Practices](http://webcms.pima.gov/cms/One.aspx?portalId=169&pageId=44283 "HIPAA/Privacy Practices")
